"NETFLIX
オリジナルシリーズ"
♪～
～♪
（春雄(はるお)の母の歌）
Okay!
（春雄の母）よし
（春雄の母の歌）
It's so trendy! Tetsuya Komuro
and Ryoko Shinohara.
（春雄の母）ナウいわあ
小室哲哉アンド篠原涼子
It's the theme song for the movie about
（春雄の母）
これ春雄がよくやってる―
ストなんとかってやつの映画の
主題歌よね？
the Street something-or-other
you're always playing.
Yeah.
（春雄）ああ
お母さんと見に行きましょうよ
Let's go see it, Haruo!
ええー？　中３で
おふくろと一緒に映画なんてやだよ
What? What middle-schooler would
want to see a movie with his mom?
ふんっ つれないわねえ
Hmph! You're so cold to me!
How will you feel if your
parent wants to see Street Fighter II?
自分の親がスト２見るとか複雑だよ
Fine then!
もういいわよ
録画した「家なき子」を見るから
I'll just watch my recording
of Homeless Child!
（春雄のため息）
（春雄の母）あーあ
Oh, If only my child was a cute girl.
うちの子もかわいい女の子だったら
一緒に映画行ってくれたかな－
I'm sure she'd see a movie with me!
It's fine!
ふーんだ
She's snapped.
（春雄）いじけちまった
AUGUST 1994
Guess, they don't have it.
（春雄）置いてねえかあ
I thought maybe they'd have it by now.
そろそろだと思ったんだが…
I guess Capcom's new fighting game
Darkstalkers, isn't out yet.
カプコンから繰り出される
最新格闘ゲーム―
「ヴァンパイア」の
稼働はまだなのか
Young miss!
（じいや）お嬢様
またここで大サボリですか
Are you playing hooky here again?
（じいや）
早くお屋敷に戻らないと―
（大野(おおの)のうなり声）
If we don't return to
the mansion quickly,
（大野(おおの)のうなり声）
私が業田(ごうだ)先生に
ぶっ飛ばされるのですぞ
Miss Goda will have my head!
私が業田(ごうだ)先生に
ぶっ飛ばされるのですぞ
DON'T HIT THE MACHINES
私が業田(ごうだ)先生に
ぶっ飛ばされるのですぞ
（大野）ふがーっ
Argh!
（じいや）
ふんがーではございません！
Don't "argh" me.
（じいや）
ふんがーではございません！
（春雄）
おいおい 何やってんだよ
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
Ah, if it isn't young master Yaguchi.
あ これは矢口(やぐち)のお坊ちゃん
（春雄）そんなムチャしてっと
人さらいだと思われるぜ
If you keep forcing her,
people will say you're a kidnapper.
ここでの騒ぎはご法度だ
Causing a ruckus here is prohibited.
It makes people go "What's that?"
and distracts them from their game.
みんな何だ？　と思って
よそ見プレーさせちゃうからなあ
Besides,
それに せっかくの夏休みに
学業だけに縛りつけられちゃ―
being bound to studies all summer
is just too pitiful.
（春雄）ふびんでしかたないよ
（じいや）うーん
I can totally understand why
it would drive the princess insane.
（春雄）お姫さんが
ご乱心になる気持ちも―
痛いほど分かる
I'll be responsible for her break time,
（春雄）お嬢様の息抜き役は
俺が務めるから―
why don't you go play Pachinko
or something?
あんたはパチンコでも
打ってこいよ
Pachinko?
（じいや）パチンコ！
（じいや）うほほーい
Time to play!
I'm sure the old man needed a break too.
（春雄）
じいやにも息抜きが必要なはずだぜ
We don't want him running over anyone.
俺以外の人間をひきかねないからな
You're 10 years too early!
（ゲーム音）
10年早いんだよ！
She uses Akira in Virtua Fighter?
「バーチャファイター」では
アキラを使うのか
同名だから
使ってると思ってたんだが…
I assumed she used him
'cause they have the same name.
コマンドがムズいキャラを
あえて使ってるようだ
But she seems to only use characters
with difficult commands.
What a terrifying game.
恐ろしいゲームだぜ
With just a five-combo,
half the stamina gauge is gone.
たった５コンボで体力ゲージを
半分以上 減らしちまう
Games could be over in
as little as six seconds.
最速で約６秒間の内に
決着がつくこともある
It comes with the added thrill
that doesn't come with 2D fighting games.
２Ｄ格闘ゲームじゃ味わえない
スリルが備わっているのだ
All right...
よし
せっかく大野がいるんだ
腕試しにいっちょやってやっか
Ono is here, after all.
I'd better at least take a shot.
ふん… 俺の影で
I'll use Kage...
Playing against Ono on a big cabinet
like this gets me fired up!
このどデカきょう体で
大野と勝負ができるのも燃えるぜ
Go!
痛えー
ぐおおおー
ひざ蹴り＆鉄山靠(てつざんこう)で―
The knee and Tetsuzanko took
a good chunk of my stamina!
かなりの体力を持っていかれた
（ゲーム音）エクセレント
Excellent!
（ゲーム音）おりゃあー！
（春雄）ぐぬぬぬぬぬ…
Fight two!
容赦ねえ女だぜ
This girl is merciless.
When does she find time to practice
with all her daily studies?
日々学業に追われているこいつは
いつゲームの腕を磨いているんだ？
She's not like me who has time
to frequent arcades.
俺みたいにしょっちゅうゲーセンに
来れる身分じゃないはずなのに
Is it just a talent she was born with?
やはり生まれもっての
天性か何かか…
（ゲーム音）ハッ！
Ah! I'm about to lose again!
（春雄）
ああーっ また負けそうだあ
ぐうーっ ううっ うぐうっ
ううっ… う？
Ring Out!
It looked like she made a misstep,
but was it on purpose?
失敗して落ちたように見えるが
わざとか？
３ラウンド分戦った方が
お互い長く遊べるからなぁ
We'll both get more play time,
if we use all three rounds.
I can't tell if she's being evil or kind,
鬼なんだか優しいんだか
分からねぇが―
俺はここであえて
鬼の戦法でいかせてもらおう！
but I'm moving forward with
a bold evil strategy!
A Koenraku into some jab punches,
弧延落(こうえんらく)からのパンチで
ピシピシやってぇの水車蹴り！
into a windmill kick!
（ゲーム音）リングアウト
リング外への押し出し勝利だぜ！
Victory by ring out!
Will that... tick her off?
と… 怒るかな？
Oh, she's not mad.
あれ？　怒らないんだ
Huh? That's unusual.
あれれ… 珍しいな
チラッ チラッ
Is she... okay?
Once the game ends,
she usually just stalks off.
いつも勝負が終わったら
すたすたどっか行っちまうのに
Is she going to finish watching me play?
俺のプレーを見届けてくれるのか？
Does she not have any friends
to play with?
あいつ 一緒に遊べる友達
いねえのかなあ
Will she be able to make friends
once she's in high school?
高校に上がったら
友達できんのかねえ？
She's strange, but gets along
surprisingly well with people.
めちゃくちゃ変わり者だし
そのくせ意外と人なつっこくて―
Yet she still seems lonely.
さみしがりの気があるもんなあ
But what should I do?
でもどうしよう…
If I put her address in the message
section of Gamest to find her friends...
ゲーメストの伝言板で
住所さらけ出して―
友達募集してたら…
I'd rather not imagine what would happen.
あんまり想像したくないなあ
TAMURA SHOP
（春雄）見ろ大野！
年末に発売されるハードの情報だ
Look Ono,
here's news about the hardware
coming out at the end of the year.
Sony's PlayStation and Sega's Sega Saturn.
ソニーから出るプレイステーション
そしてセガからのセガサターンだぜ
You can even play Virtua Fighter
on the Sega Saturn!
セガサターンにはなんと―
「バーチャファイター」が
移植されるんだ！
プレイステーションは
「リッジレーサー」や―
I hear Ridge Racer and Fantastic Parodius
are coming out on the PlayStation.
「極上パロディウスだ！」が
出るらしいけど―
But I might be in the Saturn camp.
俺はサターン派かなって
思うんだけど―
What about you?
大野はどうよ？
あ そうか
Oh, that's right.
Game consoles are forbidden
at your place, right?
お前んちは家庭用ゲーム機は
禁止なんだっけなあ
じゃ 俺が奇跡的に
手に入れることができたらよ―
Then, if I miraculously get
my hands on one,
you can come to my place to play.
またうちに遊びに来いや
（春雄）
修学旅行の時まで―
I don't know why she was so angry
until the school trip,
なんで怒られてたんか
訳分からんかったが―
but seems she's forgiven me.
That's good.
なんか許してくれたようで
よかったよかった
It really is fun being with her.
やっぱりこいつといるのは
楽しいなあ
いろいろ発見もあるし刺激的だ
I discover new things. It's stimulating.
Granny, I'll take my usual!
（春雄）
おばちゃーん いつものもらうよ
Okay, 10,000 yen.
（おばちゃん）はーい 10万円
ふんっ ありゃあ
What?
バキッと折れるはずだったんだが
That should have snapped right off.
Street Fighter II: Champion Edition,
came out while Ono was gone...
（春雄）大野がいない間に出た
スト２ダッシュ―
HyperFighting, Samurai Shodown,
Fatal Fury...
ターボ サムスピ 餓狼(がろう)伝説
I wanted to talk to her about them...
これらの話を
ずっとしたかったのだが―
いざ会うと頭からすっぽり
抜けちまうんだよなぁ
But whenever we meet, my mind goes blank.
それに俺が一方的に
しゃべるだけだろうし
Besides, it would just be me doing
the talking anyway.
Once summer break ends,
test season will be here.
夏休みが終わったら
受験シーズンが来て―
別々の高校ってか…
We'll be in separate high schools.
Coming all the way to Kawasaki
just to play Darkstalkers...
（春雄）わざわざ
「ヴァンパイア」をやりに―
川崎まで遠征だなんて
俺らも好きだよなあ
We're both true gamers.
We haven't gone somewhere together
like this since sixth grade.
お前とこうして出かけんのも
小６の時以来か
（ゲーム音）レディ ファイト
Ready, fight.
Fire!
It was just released, so there's no
multi-player. Only solo play.
（春雄）まだ稼働したばかりで
対戦じゃなく１人用だけか
Gamers huddled around a new machine
is a sight to behold!
新台に群がるゲーマー達のこの光景
I can't contain my excitement!
わくわくしてたまんねぇよな
なんて滑らかで美しい動きなんだ
What beautiful, smooth movements.
Looks like a really amazing fighting game
has arrived.
すげぇ格ゲーが登場しやがったなあ
ごくっ
（ゲーム音）レディ ファイト
Ready, fight.
（春雄）うおお　動きが軽い
The movements are light!
そしてすごくコミカルだ
And so comical!
（ゲーム音）うおっ
Each character's moves look really tricky.
各キャラの動きが
トリッキーすぎて―
Looks like I'll have plenty of
studying to do.
勉強しなきゃ
いかんことだらけだな
（ゲーム音）うおおーっ
俺の持ちキャラは
このビシャモンで決まりそうだぜ
I'd say it's decided,
my main character is this Bishamon.
俺の持ちキャラは
このビシャモンで決まりそうだぜ
Just like Guile,
ガイルさんと同様
長い付き合いになりそうだ
it'll be a long-term relationship.
（ゲーム音）レディ ファイト
Ready, fight.
Ono's playing with a heavy character,
not surprising.
（春雄）
大野はやはり重量級か
She seems to be fixated on characters
with 360 joystick punch throws.
レバー１回転パンチの投げキャラが
身に染みついてんだなぁ
（ゲーム音）うおおおーっ
（観客のどよめき）
S-She cleared the whole thing.
（春雄）って 全クリかい
OPEN YOUR EYES, DOCTOR
It's her first time and she played to
the end with no losses.
初プレイなのに完封で
エンディングを迎えやがったぜ
Incredible as always.
相も変わらず魅せるせてくれる
退屈しねぇなぁ
I never get bored with you.
（春雄）164メガトン？
164 Megatons!
中学女子で ありえんのかこれ…
This can't be feasible for
a middle school girl.
（大野）ふう…
You look pleased.
（春雄）ご満悦だなあ
This didn't stem from your hatred of me,
did it?
俺に対する憎しみの表れじゃ
ねぇだろうな
It's almost time
もうすぐ中学最後の夏休みも
終わってしまう…
for our last summer break in
middle school to end.
もうすぐ中学最後の夏休みも
終わってしまう…
（ゲーム音）頑張ってね
もうすぐ中学最後の夏休みも
終わってしまう…
Nice shot! Good job!
（ゲーム音）ナイスショット
やったね
（春雄）おっ
RICEBALL-SHAPED ERASER
Hey, Ono.
（春雄）なあ 大野
You're testing for Joran High School,
right?
お前 あの上蘭(じょうらん)高校を受けるんだろ？
I don't care which school I go to
as long as I get in,
俺は高校なんか
入ればどこでもいいけど―
but you've got it rough.
お前は大変だよなぁ
I guess my duties as your summer break
stress relief manager are over.
夏休みのお嬢様の息抜き役も
これで終わりか
You won't be able to just go out
and be carefree like this.
今までみたいに
気軽に出かけたりできなくなるなぁ
さっきプレイした
「ヴァンパイア」も―
That Darkstalkers game we just played
will get even more hyped.
これから盛り上がるだろうし―
And I heard Virtua Fighter 2 is coming
at the end of the year.
年末には「バーチャファイター２」
が来ると聞く
And Samurai Shodown II was announced
by Neo Geo.
ネオジオから―
「真サムライスピリッツ」も
予定してて―
I hear they're releasing
The King of Fighters '94 as well.
「ザ･キング･オブ･
ファイターズ’ 94」なるものも―
発売するらしい
この前見せたプレイステーションと
セガサターンも控えているし―
The PlayStation and Sega Saturn
are on their way, too.
It's inevitable, it's going to be
a turbulent era for gamers.
ゲーマーにとって激動の時代を
迎えようとしていることは必至だ
All these wonderful events...
そんなすばらしいイベントに―
俺達は受験という人生初の
別れ道が待ってるんだもんなあ
But we're standing at the fork in the road
with these milestone exams.
We're going now, Young Miss.
（じいや）発車しますよ お嬢様
Ono...
（春雄）大野
Do you...
お前 俺と一緒にいて―
enjoy...
being with me?
楽しいか？
発車オ～ラ～イ！
We're clear for takeoff!
（春雄）あいつが高校に入って―
If she gets to high school,
and is all alone...
１人でいるようなら―
I'd help her out, even if I'm just
a good pastime for her.
いい気晴らし役にでも
俺がなってやって…
いや…
No...
Who am I kidding?
本音はそうじゃねえだろ
Be honest with yourself.
自分に正直になれ
I...
俺は…
あいつと一緒にいてえと
思っているんだ
want to stay with her.
（春雄の母）春雄…
Haruo.
For you to take initiative and dive
into schoolwork...
あんたが率先して
学業に打ち込むなんて…
I just wet myself and threw up
at the same time in surprise.
お母さんは驚きでおしっこを
漏らしながらゲボが出そうよ
Empty head of mine, focus on studying!
（春雄）空っぽの俺の頭よ
勉学にいそしめ
ぐうっ 何だこりゃ？
コマンド表か？
What is this? Commands?
I'm good at remembering
this kind of stuff,
こういう記憶力は
ずばぬけているのに―
学業のことは
まるで頭に入らないんだもんなあ
but academics never seem to stick.
Why not do some mental exercises
before studying?
（キャラＡ）勉強する前に
頭の体操はどうかね？
（キャラＢ）己を一新する前に
ゲームから一新してみては？
Why not focus on games before focusing
on yourself?
（ギース）しょうゆという字を
覚えたくば－－
If you want to remember the characters
for "soy sauce," you should...
ギースにしょうゆと
覚えるがいい！
（春雄）だっ だめだ
ゲームの脳みそが邪魔をする
I-It's no use!
My game-brain is getting in the way!
（春雄）だっ だめだ
ゲームの脳みそが邪魔をする
CONTRADICTIONS
NOVEMBER
What? You're applying
to Joran High School?
（小春(こはる)）
ええっ 上蘭高校を受けるの？
You?
矢口君が？
Are you serious, Haruo?
（宮尾(みやお)）マジかよ春雄！
Joran High School is that school
with super high requirements, right?
上蘭高校といえば―
あの偏差値が
めちゃめちゃ高いとこだろ？
Why did you change your mind?
どんな心境の変化なの？
Shouldn't you always have a higher goal
set as your ideal choice?
どうせなら第１志望は
レベルが高い方がいいだろ？
Anyway, I just want to challenge myself.
とにかく俺は挑戦したいんだよ
今まで学業から目を背けてきた分―
You'll have to work ten times harder
to make up for all the studying
you've shirked until now.
何十倍も努力しなきゃなんだぞ
（春雄）分かってるよ
I know.
They told me that at
the parent-teacher conference.
それは三者面談でも言われたし…
PARENT-TEACHER CONFERENCE
（遠野(とおの)先生）正直な話―
To be honest,
今まで学業を怠ってきた矢口君が―
with all the studying he's neglected
up to this point,
この短期間で取り戻せるとは
到底思えません
I find it unlikely he'll be able
to make it up in time.
I think it's a rash move.
無謀な考えだと思ってます
I...
私もまっ…
absolutely agree with you.
…たく同じ意見です
I thought it was a fool's errand
in the first place.
バカがバカをこじらせた狂気だと
最初は感じました
Mom...
おふくろ…
（遠野先生）ただ この無謀は
悪いことではないと思います
But... I don't think this rash move
is a bad thing.
大事なのは現状を変えようとする
矢口君の姿勢です
What's important is the fact
he is trying to change.
Seems you've worked hard on
your homework over the summer.
夏休みの宿題は
真面目に取り組んだみたいだし―
I was impressed.
私は感心しました
そう！
私も感心してたんすよ先生～
Yes, I was impressed too, Miss Tono!
Yaguchi, what led you to change
your course so drastically?
矢口君
矢口君をここまで変える
きっかけって―
何だったの？
I'm sure it's the love of a woman.
（春雄の母）
きっと女への愛でしょうね
（春雄）うっ
（春雄の母）私という女への
And that woman is me!
おふくろはちょっと黙っててくれよ
Mom, could you not talk for a moment?
Then it wouldn't be a parent-teacher
conference, right?
それじゃ三者面談に
ならないじゃないの
おふくろが話すと
ややこしくなるんだよ
Whenever you open your mouth,
things get weird.
（遠野先生）矢口君
（春雄）あ…
Yaguchi.
Huh?
To get into your top-pick school,
you'll need extraordinary determination.
第１志望校に入るには
並大抵ではない努力が必要です
I'll fight alongside you until that
determination bears results.
努力が結果に結びつくまで
先生も一緒に戦っていきます
先生…
Miss Tono...
（春雄の母）11月に―
Virtua Fighter2 comes out in November,
you sure you'll be okay?
「バーチャファイター２」が
出るけど大丈夫かなあ？
な… 何言ってんだよおふくろ！
Wha-What are you talking about, Mom?
How come you know that?
てか 何で知ってんだよ
頑張りましょう 矢口君
Let's do our best, Yaguchi.
Right.
（春雄）はい
年末には次世代機の
セガサターンと―
The next-gen Sega Saturn and PlayStation
come out at the end of the year,
プレイステーションが出るのに
正気か？
have you lost it?
その刺激的な名称を言うのは
やめてくれ
Don't talk like it's the end
of the world for me.
If I recall,
you got pretty engrossed, too.
っていうかお前も
詳しくなったな宮尾
Miyao is right.
宮尾君の言うとおりだよ
Right when the gaming world's
getting exciting?
ゲーム業界が
盛り上がっている時に―
一体どうしちゃったの？
What happened?
A half year of patience isn't
such a big deal.
約半年の辛抱なんて
どうってことねぇぜ
Ah, Haruo, are you...
あっ！　春雄 お前もしかして…
（宮尾）大野さんと一緒の高校に…
trying to go to the same school as Ono...
Huh?
あ？
春雄！　俺でよければ
いつでも勉強教えてやるからな！
Haruo, if you want,
I'll tutor you anytime!
（小春）うう… 私も教えてあげたい
I want to tutor him too!
（チャイム）
HARUO YAGUCHI
（春雄の母）はあ～
春雄がまっすぐ
学校から帰ってきて勉強するなんて
Haruo actually came straight home
from school to study.
信じられなくてお母さん
泡吹きそう
Your mother is practically sobbing
in disbelief.
（春雄）
小学校の頃の勉強を今するとはなあ
I can't believe I'm doing elementary
school stuff now.
It's best to find a subject you like and
grow outward from there.
（小春）勉強は好きな教科から
まず伸ばすことがコツだよ
That'd be Japanese.
（春雄）国語だな 好きっていうか
一番とっつきやすい
But I wouldn't say I like it,
just not as daunting.
Rather than studying long hours,
（遠野先生）長時間の勉強より
集中する１時間を作りなさい
try setting aside one hour
of increased focus.
What about increased focus for
longer hours, Teach?
（春雄）集中の長時間
ってのはどうだい？　先生
（宮尾）
毎日運動するのもおすすめだぞ
I recommend exercising every day, too.
It gets the blood circulating
through the brain.
脳の血液を循環させるんだ
（春雄）
今日も走ってきたぞ 宮尾
I ran today, Miyao.
おっ　おう…
Haruo, Haruo!
（ゲーム機Ａ）春雄君 春雄君
（ゲーム機Ｂ）
最近全然つれないじゃんかよ
You've been distant with us lately.
（ゲーム機Ｃ）
僕たちをやると楽しいよ
You'll have fun if you play with us!
（春雄）ちょーっと静かに
しておくれ ごめんな
Be quiet for a bit, okay?
Sorry, guys.
（ゲーム機たちの泣き声）
（ゲームの音声）
OCTOBER
（男Ａ）あのめちゃ強い子
調子悪いみてぇだな
That super strong girl doesn't seem
like she's in top form.
（男Ｂ）
夏に何十連勝もしていたのに…
She had a crazy win streak back
in the summer.
Is she in a slump?
（男Ａ）スランプってやつか
Young miss...
お嬢様…
（宮尾）春雄 お前まるで基本が
頭に入ってないじゃないか
Haruo... you don't even have
the basics down!
（春雄）頼むから
怒らないで教えておくれえ
Please, will you teach me
without getting mad?
Yaguchi really stopped coming
to play games.
（小春）矢口君 本当にゲーム
やりに来なくなっちゃったな
And it looks like something major
came out.
何か大作が出たっぽいのに
He's really that serious about this.
それだけ本気ってことなんだね
SEGA SATURN
ON SALE TODAY
NOVEMBER
（じいや）お嬢様…
Young Miss...
PLAYSTATION
ON SALE TODAY
DECEMBER
JANUARY, 1995
FEBRUARY
EXAM DAY
（春雄の母）４万4800円
（春雄）え？
44,800 yen.
Huh?
（春雄の母）春雄が欲しがってた
セガサターンの値段
The price of the Sega Saturn you wanted.
勉強しないでもし―
If you'd come saying "buy it"
without even studying,
「買ってくれ」の「か」の字でも
言うようなら―
鉄拳をくらわすところだった
you would have caught these fists.
でも今の春雄なら問答無用で
買い与えちゃう
But for Haruo, I just want to buy it.
No questions asked.
You've been working so very hard for this!
だってものすごく
今日まで頑張ってたんだもーん
甘やかすな甘やかすな
Stop babying me.
バカ息子がつけあがるだけだ
It's just gonna go to my head.
Haruo!
（春雄の母）春雄－！
Huh?
あっ
Young master, Yaguchi.
矢口のお坊ちゃん
I've come to pick you up.
お迎えにあがりましたよ
Huh, why? What for?
えっ なんで？　お迎えって…
今日の行き先は
お嬢様と同じでございましょう？
Isn't your destination the same as
the Young Miss' today?
（春雄の母）
おほほほほほ～
（じいや）町でお坊ちゃんの
お母様と偶然お会いし―
I met your mother by coincidence
in town and heard about it from her.
（春雄の母）
おほほほほほ～
コソコソっと教えてくれました
おふくろのやつペラペラと…
My dang mom, running her mouth...
（じいや）私は聞いて安心しました
（春雄）え？
I was relieved when I heard it.
To you and the Young Miss,
arcades are the bridge between you.
お坊ちゃんとお嬢様にとって
ゲームセンターは―
お２人の架け橋
姿を現さなくなった
お坊ちゃんの心は―
I was worried when you stopped showing up
that your heart had gone somewhere
far off.
遠く離れていってしまったのではと
心配してたのです
Even being in the arcades she loves
so much,
お嬢様はお好きであられる
ゲームセンターにいながらも―
心ここにあらずでした
her mind was elsewhere.
なぜだか分かりますか？
Do you know why?
Why?
なぜだ？
（じいや）お嬢様は時々
架け橋の場へ出向いて―
The Young Miss would occasionally
go to these bridges and wait for you!
あなたが来るのを
待っていたのですぞ！
（春雄）あ…
You are a pillar in the Young Miss' life.
（じいや）お嬢様にとっての
お坊ちゃんは―
心のよりどころでございます
A support for her to escape her
harsh everyday life.
日々鍛錬のつらさを癒やす
支えなのです
お坊ちゃんの受験の話は
お嬢様にはお伝えしておりません
I haven't told her about your plans
to take the test.
Go ahead, you should tell her yourself.
どうぞ ご自身でお話ください
（春雄）バ…
The...
「バーチャファイター２」の
導入日にな
The day Virtua Fighter 2 came out,
I thought I might take a break
and went to check it out.
ちょっと息抜きに
様子だけ見に行ったんだよ
本当に圧巻だった
It was really incredible.
I've been away from arcades for a bit,
しばらくゲーセンから
離れてたから―
なめらかな人物の動きと
移動する背景にクラクラきたよ
so the smooth character movements,
moving scenery made my head spin.
The Kung-Fu in you is lacking.
（ゲームの音声）
I want to fight strong people!
（春雄）あれぞ格ゲー界の…
いや ゲーム界の革命だった
For the fighting game world, no...
for the gaming world, it was a revolution.
３Ｄに負けじと
２Ｄもすさまじかった
The 2D games have been really
keeping up with the 3D ones, though.
They keep improving, it makes me wonder if
I'll be able to keep up.
進化し続けて―
これからついていけんのか
不安になるくらいな
ゲーマーにとって
脳がとろける進化だ
For a gamer, these improvements
are mind-boggling.
俺達ガキが―
I see arcades as a great place
for kids like us
時代の変化を
目の当たりにできる場所ってのは―
to bear witness to the changing of eras.
ゲーセンなんじゃねえのかって
俺は感じたぜ
That's how I felt.
昔 空港でさ―
I said there would be
countless things that we can't even
imagine coming out,
俺たちが
想像もつかねえようなものが―
どんどん出るだろうって
俺が言ったの覚えてっか？
do you remember that?
I thought if I could witness
この大きな流れを
大野と見ていけたら―
this great change with you,
I'd have the time of my life.
どんなに楽しいかと本気で思ったんだよ
I've been doing all this test preparation
I'm still not used to.
今までずっと
慣れない受験勉強をしてよ
I've just been exercising restraint.
自粛してただけでゲーセンに
飽きたわけでも何でもないんだよ
It's not that I've given up
going to arcades.
Back then, when things were getting
really exciting,
この一番
盛り上がってる時期に―
parting with games was harder than ever.
ゲームから離れるのは
何ともたまらんかった
誘惑の渦に
何度もダイブしかけたしな
There were lots of times I was almost
lured back in.
The gaming world will keep advancing,
ゲーム業界はどんどん前進して―
大野も前へ進んでるのに―
and you're moving forward, too.
I'd be pretty lame if I only
stayed static.
俺だけとどまるなんて
かっこつかねぇだろ？
I knew I was being reckless.
無謀だと思ったけど―
But I'm going to try to get into
Joran High School, same as you.
俺 大野と同じ
上蘭高校を受けるんだ
A fool is just foolishly trying
to climb higher.
バカはバカなりに
あがいてみようかって
あ…
お…
Ono... I...
大野… 俺な…
No...
いや…
Never mind, it's nothing.
やっぱ 何でもねえ
PRIVATE ACADEMY JORAN
ENTRANCE EXAM
♪～
AKIRA ONO
TEST NUMBER 1940
HARUO YAGUCHI
TEST NUMBER 1942
（春雄）1942…
1942...
It's a good number.
いい番号だ
I need to go all in to make sure
I don't get shot down
撃墜されてゲームオーバーに
ならぬよう気合いを入れろ
and get a game over.
Let's do this.
やってやるぜ
I've answered all the easier questions.
難易度の低いものから
すべて克服した
（ギース）
ギースにしょうゆ
Did you remember, "Geese in soy sauce"?
覚えてっか？
（春雄）
しょうゆという問題はないが―
There aren't any soy sauce questions,
but thank you.
心強い
I'll clear it one at a time.
１つ１つクリアしていく
そして
もし受かったら―
Then...
If I manage to get in...
I can tell Ono...
大野に俺の… 正直な気持ちを…
my true feelings.
PRIVATE ACADEMY JORAN HEISEI YEAR 7
ACCEPTANCE LIST
～♪
（春雄）男子三日で何とかって
言うよなあ
They say give a boy three days.
It means if you don't see them for a while
they'll be totally different.
しばらく会わないと―
とんでもなく変わってるって
話だが―
女子はどうだ？
What about girls?
夏休み終わったらいきなり
金髪になってたとか―
Sometimes they turn blonde after
summer break.
あるあるだが―
なあ 日高
お前はどうなんだ？
Right, Hidaka? How about you?
♪～
～♪
Subtitle translation by
Emily Noguchi